A Guide to the Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 10, Accession 2019:126 FA1730
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation records, Record Group 10, Accession 2019:126
2000-2017
Rockefeller Archive Center
Henry Luce Foundation
FA1730
1 Cassettes
11.88 Cubic Feet 27 letter-sized document boxes
Biographical / Historical
The Henry Luce Foundation was established by Henry R. Luce in 1936. As a New York-based nonprofit organization, the Luce Foundation awards grants in American Art, Asian studies, Higher Education, Theology, and supports the Clare Boothe Luce Program for women in science, mathematics, and engineering.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Henry Luce Foundation in 2019.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Luce Foundation records (Record Group 10) consists primarily of grant files.
Arrangement
The Henry Luce Foundation records (Record Group 10) are arranged as received.
Religions; International relations; Art, American; Education, Higher; Environmental sciences; Theology -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.
- America Abroad Media - Public Radio Programming on Religion and Public Life in the Middle East and South Asia, 2012-2016 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Council of Learned Societies - Capstone Conference and Publication Evaluating the Luce Fund for Asian Studies, 2006-2016 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Council of Learned Societies - Publication on Asian Studies in Liberal Education in the 21st Century, 2008-2016 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Council of Learned Societies - Vietnam Educational Exchange Program, 2004-2016 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American University - Religious Engagement with Rights and Justice in Latin America: Environment and Gender, 2013-2016 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Aquinas Institute of Theology - Montesinos Fellowship, 2013-2016 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Archdiocese of Chicago - Theological and Communication Experts in the 2015 Roman Synod, 2015-2016 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Asbury Theological Seminary - World Christian Identities Research and Scholarly Networks in Africa, Asia, and South America, 2011-2016 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
- Asia Foundation - Luce Scholars' Summer Language Training in Asia, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Association of Art Museum Curators - Travel Grants for Annual Meetings, 2014-2016 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
- Auburn Theological Seminary - Auburn Fellows Program for Religious Leaders, 2014-2016 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
- Autry National Center of the American West - "Floral Journey: Native North American Beadwork" Exhibition and Catalog, 2013-2016 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Brooklyn Historical Society - George B. Post and Related Architectural Drawings Project, 2014-2016 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Bureau for International Reporting - Fault Lines of Faith Reporting Series, 2015-2016 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- California State University, Fullerton - Leadership Institute for Tomorrow Pilot Year, 2014-2016 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Center for Strategic and International Studies - Religion and Democracy in Africa, 2012-2016 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
- Central Baptist Theological Seminary - Myanmar Institute of Technology Joint Program, 2012-2016 (Box 4, Box 22-23)
- Central Baptist Theological Seminary - Myanmar Institute of Technology Joint Program - Global Immersion in Pluralistic World (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
- Chautauqua Institution - New Clergy Program, 2013-2015 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Cleveland Museum of Art - Chinese Paintings: Masterworks from the Cleveland Museum of Art Publication, 2013-2016 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Colby College Museum of Art - Reinterpret and Reinstall the American Art Collection, 2013-2016 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Columbia University - Mission Research Library and the William Adams Brown Ecumenical Archive, Burke Library, 2010-2015 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
- Columbia University - Center for the Study of Democracy, Toleration, and Religion (Renewal), 2013-2016 (Box 5, Folder 29-30)
- Columbia University - Local Faith Communities' Engagement in Humanitarian Response Study, 2013-2016 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Commonweal Foundation - Theological Writing Project (Renewal), 2012-2015 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Cooper-Hewitt National Design Museum, Smithsonian Institution - Reinterpret and Reinstall the American Art Collection, 2013-2016 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Council of Independent Colleges - New Governance Education Program, 2015-2016 (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
- Drew University - Dictionary for the Study of Religion in English and Chinese, 2000-2015 (Box 6, Folder 36-37)
- Drexel University, College of Medicine - Executive Leadership in Academic Technology and Engineering (ELATE) Program, 2012-2016 (Box 6, Folder 38)
- Duke University - Material Religion: State of the Art Conference, 2013-2016 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Duke Divinity School - Theology of Christian and Muslim Peacemaking Seminars, 2012-2016 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Eastern Mennonite University - Visiting Professors of Islam and Judaism, Center for Interfaith Engagement, 2011-2014 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Educational Broadcasting Corporation-Thirteen/WNET - Enhanced Coverage of Foreign Affairs on "Religion & Ethics Newsweekly", 2007-2011 (Box 7, Folder 42-43)
- Episcopal Divinity School - Faculty Training, Curricular Revisions, and Online Continuing Education on Religious Pluralism, 2011-2016 (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
- Filmmakers Collaborative Inc. - Death by Design Documentary, 2013-2016 (Box 8, Folder 46)
- Fordham University - Clare Boothe Luce Program 25th Anniversary Conference, 2014-2016 (Box 8, Folder 47)
- Fuller Theological Seminary - Online Journal for Interfaith Dialogue, 2012-2016 (Box 8, Folder 48-50)
- George Washington University - Religion and International Affairs in Central Eurasia, 2014-2016 (Box 8, Folder 51)
- Gibbes Museum of Art - Reinstall and Reinterpret the Permanent Collection, 2014-2016 (Box 8, Folder 52)
- Hartford Seminary - Contemporary Islam Professorship, 2010-2015 (Box 9, Folder 53-54)
- Harvard University - Pluralism, Coexistence, and Conflict in Muslim-Majority Countries Research Network, 2010-2014 (Box 9, Folder 55)
- Herstory Writers Workshop - Memoir Writing, 2014-2016 (Box 9, Folder 56)
- Dietrich von Hildebrand Legacy Project - Website, 2011-2015 (Box 9, Folder 57)
- Hong Kong-American Center, Ltd. - Religion and Public Life in China, 2006-2016 (Box 9, Folder 58-59)
- Human Media (Connie Goldman Productions) - "Humankind" Public Radio Series, 2011-2016 (Box 10, Folder 60)
- Human Media (Connie Goldman Productions) - "Humankind" Public Radio Series (Renewal), 2012-2016 (Box 10, Folder 61)
- Human Media (Connie Goldman Productions) - "Humankind" Public Radio Series (Renewal), 2014-2016 (Box 10, Folder 62)
- Interfaith Center of New York - "A Haggadah for All Seasons: A Jewish, Christian and Muslim Dialogue on the Exodus", 2009-2016 (Box 10, Folder 63-64)
- Jesuit School of Theology, Santa Clara University - Pilot Program for Catholic Women from Asia (Women of Wisdom and Action Initiative), 2012-2015 (Box 10, Folder 65-67)
- Johns Hopkins University, School of Advanced International Studies - Strengthening Coverage of Religion and International Affairs in the United States Media, 2010-2016 (Box 11, Folder 68-69)
- Johns Hopkins University, School of Advanced International Studies - Strengthening Coverage of Religion and Internation Affairs in the United States Media (Renewal), 2012-2016 (Box 11, Folder 70)
- Johns Hopkins University - Support Chinese Language Instruction at the Hopkins-Nanjing Center, 2010-2016 (Box 11, Folder 71-72)
- LaGuardia Community College - World Pathways Heritage Language Program, 2015-2017 (Box 11, Folder 73)
- Lancaster Theological Seminary - Collaborative Program on Religious Pluralism with the Institute of Religion, Culture, and Peace of Payap University, 2010-2016 (Box 12, Folder 74-76)
- Lancaster Theological Seminary - Collaboration with Partners for Sacred Places, 2013-2016 (Box 12, Folder 77)
- Leiden University - "Asian Studies in Africa: Challenges and Prospects of a New Axis of Intellectual Interactions" Conference, 2014-2016 (Box 12, Folder 78)
- Loyola Marymount University - Educational Activities Promoting Ecumenism between Orthodox and Roman Catholic Churches, 2009-2016 (Box 13, Folder 79-81)
- Loyola Marymount University - "Modern Asian Drama: An Anthology", 2012-2016 (Box 13, Folder 82)
- Lutheran Theological Seminary, Philadelphia - Asian Theological Institute, 2009-2016 (Box 13, Folder 83)
- Maryland Public Television - "Chaplains" Public Television Program, 2011-2015 (Box 14, Folder 84-85)
- Meadville Lombard Theological School - Integrated Community Model of Religious Formation, 2011-2015 (Box 14, Folder 86-87)
- Memphis Theological Seminary - Theology and Arts Program, 2011-2016 (Box 14, Folder 88-89)
- Middle East Institute - Religion and Middle East Policy Formation, 2012-2016 (Box 14, Folder 90)
- Milwaukee Art Museum - Reinstall American Art Collection for the 125th Anniversary, 2012-2016 (Box 14, Folder 91)
- National Academy of Sciences - "Women's Adventures in Science" Book Series, 2005-2010 (Box 15, Folder 92)
- National Academy of Sciences - Website Expansion Aimed at Increasing Young Women's Interest in Careers in the Sciences, 2006-2010 (Box 15, Folder 93)
- National Academy of Sciences - Scoping Workshop on Sexual Harassment of Early Career Researchers in STEM, 2016 (Box 15, Folder 94)
- New Britain Museum of American Art - Reinstall and Reinterpret the Permanent Collection, 2014-2016 (Box 15, Folder 95)
- New Orleans Museum of Art - Refurbish the American Decorative Art Galleries, 2010-2016 (Box 15, Folder 96)
- New York University - Scholars at Risk Network 2016 Global Congress, Universities in a Dangerous World (Box 15, Folder 97)
- Northern Illinois University - International Cambodian Studies Conference, DeKalb Illinois, 2012-2016 (Box 15, Folder 98)
- Northwestern University - Thinking about Religion, Law, and Politics, 2014-2016 (Box 15, Folder 99)
- NUS America Foundation (Yale) - Innovation in Liberal Arts Curricula, 2015-2016 (Box 16, Folder 100-101)
- Odyssey Networks - Series of Commentaries on the Christian Lectionary by Biblical Scholars and Ministers through the Lens of Current Events, 2013-2015 (Box 16, Folder 102-104)
- Odyssey Networks - Series of Commentaries on the Christian Lectionary by Biblical Scholars and Ministers through the Lens of Current Events - Serving Life (Box 16, Folder 102-104)
- Odyssey Networks - Series of Commentaries on the Christian Lectionary by Biblical Scholars and Ministers through the Lens of Current Events - The Power of Stories (Box 16, Folder 102-104)
- Payap University - Institute for Religion, Culture, and Peace and Faculty Development in the McGilvary College of Divinity, 2007-2015 (Box 17, Folder 105-108)
- Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts - "Peter Blume: Nature and Metamorphosis" Exhibition and Catalog, 2012-2013 (Box 17, Folder 109)
- Perkins School of Theology - Center for the Study of Latino/a Christianity and Religions, 2007-2016 (Box 18, Folder 110-111)
- Perkins School of Theology - Center for the Study of Latino/a Christianity and Religions (Renewal), 2011-2016 (Box 18, Box 112-113)
- Philadelphia Museum of Art - Digitize American Prints Collection, 2012-2016 (Box 18, Folder 114-115)
- Philanthropy New York - Headquarters Relocation, 2014-2016 (Box 19, Folder 116)
- The Phillips Collection - "Made in the USA: American Masterworks from The Phillips Collection" Catalog, 2012-2014 (Box 19, Folder 117)
- Prospect New Orleans, U.S. Biennial, Inc. -"Basquiat and the Bayou" Exhibition and Catalog, 2013-2016 (Box 19, Folder 118)
- Public Radio International - Coverage of Religion and International Affairs on "The World", 2008-2010 (Box 19, Folder 119)
- Pulitzer Center for Crisis Reporting - Religion in Power Campaign, 2013-2016 (Box 19, Folder 120)
- Queens Library Foundation - Acquisition of Asian Materials for the International Resource Center, 2014-2016 (Box 19, Folder 121)
- Reconstructionist Rabbinical College - Multifaith Training Program, 2010-2016 (Box 20, Folder 122-124)
- Religion Newswriters Foundation - Training for Journalists Covering Religion and International Affairs, 2007-2010 (Box 20, Folder 125)
- Rice University - Commerical and Civic Advertising in Asia Research Project and Digital Archive, Chao Center for Asain Studies, 2010-2016 (Box 21, Folder 126-128)
- Saint John's University, Collegeville - Hill Museum and Manuscript Library Web Developer, 2014-2016 (Box 21, Folder 129)
- Saint Paul School of Theology - Faculty Position in Native American Studies in Church and Society, 2010-2015 (Box 21, Folder 130)
- Seattle University of Theology and Ministry - Education Model for Ministry in a Religiously Diverse World, 2011-2015 (Box 21, Folder 131)
- Social Science Research Council - Religion and International Affairs (Renewal), 2009-2016 (Box 22, Folder 132-133)
- Social Science Research Council - Two-Day Religion and International Affairs Workshop, 2010-2016 (Box 22, Folder 134)
- Social Science Research Council - Religion, Media, and Digitization Project, 2013-2016 (Box 22, Folder 135)
- Society of Biblical Literature - Independent Network of Qur'anic Scholars, 2012-2015 (Box 22, Folder 136-138)
- Society of Women Engineers - American Leadership for Women in Engineering Program, 2015-2016 (Box 23, Folder 139)
- Stanford University, Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences - Symposium on Knowledge Production and Dissemination, 2015 (Box 23, Folder 140)
- Staten Island Museum - "Staten Island Seen" Exhibition, 2012-2016 (Box 23, Folder 141)
- Syracuse University - English Language Training Program on Science and Civil Society, 2014-2015 (Box 23, Folder 142)
- Tanenbaum Center - Peacemakers in Action Volume 2, 2015-2016 (Box 23, Folder 143)
- The Tides Center - China Dialogue, 2008-2010 (Box 23, Folder 144)
- Union Theological Seminary - Professor of Islamic Studies, 2010-2015 (Box 23, Folder 145-146)
- Union Theological Seminary - Enlightenment and Liberation: Engaged Buddhist and Liberation Theologians in Dialogue Conference, 2013-2016 (Box 24, Folder 147)
- University of California, Berkeley - Green Governance, Green Peace: International Exchange in Environmental Governance, Community Resource Management, and Conflict Resolution, 2004-2016 (Box 24, Folder 148-150)
- University of California, Berkeley - Journal of Vietnamese Studies (Renewal), 2009-2017 (Box 24, Folder 151)
- University of California, Berkeley - Politics of Religion Freedom: Contested Norms and Local Practices, 2010-2013 (Box 25, Folder 152-154)
- University of California, Irvine - Charity, Representation, and Humanitarianism in Africa: Religious and Secular Perspectives, 2011-2016 (Box 25, Folder 155)
- University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign - Communication and Dissemination of International Service Learning in US Institutions of Higher Educations (Box 25, Folder 156)
- University of Pittsburgh - Religious Institutions and Voices in International Development, 2008-2012 (Box 25, Folder 157)
- University of Southern California - Young Muslim Leaders Curricula and Network, 2012-2016 (Box 26, Folder 158)
- University of Wisconsin Foundation - "Tales From Planet Earth" Environmental Studies Film Festival, 2015-2016 (Box 26, Folder 159)
- Virginia Theological Seminary - Understanding between Muslim and Christian Communities, 2011-2015 (Box 26, Folder 160-161)
- Washington University, St. Louis - Migration of First-Year College Students Out of STEM Fields, 2011-2016 (Box 26, Folder 162-163)
- Westmoreland Museum of American Art - Reinstall American Art Collection, 2015-2016 (Box 27, Folder 164)
- Wheaton College - Changing Face of American Evangelicalism, 2003-2015 (Box 27, Folder 165)
- World Student Christian Federation - Leadership Training Program, Chevy Chase, Maryland, 2014-2015 (Box 27, Folder 166)
- Yale University - Women, Religion, and Globalization Program, 2007-2011 (Box 27, Folder 167-168)
- Yale University, Center for Material and Visual Cultures of Religion - Website Redesign, 2015-2016 (Box 27, Folder 169)